<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>Micah&#x27;s Secret Blog - programming</title>
    <subtitle>An assortment of my ramblings and random adventures.</subtitle>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://micahkepe.com/blog/categories/programming/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://micahkepe.com/blog"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2024-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://micahkepe.com/blog/categories/programming/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>[6] How Do Software Packages Work?</title>
        <published>2024-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://micahkepe.com/blog/software-packages/"/>
        <id>https://micahkepe.com/blog/software-packages/</id>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;How do software packages work behind the scenes? How are they created, distributed, and installed? In this post, we&#x27;ll explore the lifecycle of software packages, from creation to installation, using the Node Package Manager (NPM) and the Autoprefixer package as real-world examples.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</summary>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>[5] Bloom Filters: Space-Efficient Probabilistic Data Structures</title>
        <published>2024-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://micahkepe.com/blog/bloom-filters/"/>
        <id>https://micahkepe.com/blog/bloom-filters/</id>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the realm of computer science, efficiency is often the key to solving complex
problems. One elegant solution that stands out for its efficiency is the Bloom
filter. Despite being relatively lesser-known, Bloom filters offer a powerful
method for determining set membership while using minimal space. This post
explores what Bloom filters are, how they work, their applications in various
fields, and compares them with other data structures.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</summary>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>[4] WebP: A Case Study in the Hidden Vulnerabilities of Image Formats</title>
        <published>2024-05-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-05-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://micahkepe.com/blog/webp-vulnerability/"/>
        <id>https://micahkepe.com/blog/webp-vulnerability/</id>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hacked by an image? How could that be possible? This is the story of how a
seemingly innocuous image format, WebP, was discovered to have a critical
vulnerability that could be exploited to execute arbitrary code on a victim&#x27;s
machine.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</summary>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>[3] Ingenious Algorithms We Take for Granted: PageRank, Spell Checkers, and Shazam</title>
        <published>2024-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://micahkepe.com/blog/ingenious-algorithms/"/>
        <id>https://micahkepe.com/blog/ingenious-algorithms/</id>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Algorithms are all around us. They are the invisible forces that power our
modern world, from the search engines we use to find information to the social
networks we use to connect with friends and family. In this post, I share some
ingenious algorithms that I have learned about both in courses and through my
own research.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</summary>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>[2] Biggest Takeaways from The Missing Semester of Your CS Education</title>
        <published>2024-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://micahkepe.com/blog/missing-semester/"/>
        <id>https://micahkepe.com/blog/missing-semester/</id>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Nearly a year ago, I took an online course called
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;missing.csail.mit.edu&#x2F;&quot;&gt;The Missing Semester of Your CS Education&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The
course was created by a group of MIT students and covers a wide range of topics
that are often overlooked in traditional computer science curriculums. The
course is designed to help students become more productive and efficient
programmers by teaching them essential skills that are not typically taught in
school.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</summary>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
